Douglas Falcão

Summary

Brazilian/Portuguese Nacional, with 37 years of age, 13 of which have been focused on building automated solutions from the ground up, to administering systems and mapping out business needs while bridging the gap between the business side and IT Teams. Experienced Python Developer, driven to automate tasks and analysis with Pandas and Selenium. Currently a Digital Transformation Specialist, who is also the technical lead of a 6 person team focused on automating numerous reports for Controlled Pharmaceutical Substances to LatAm countries authorities.

Santo André, SP - Brazil Mobile: +55 11 98258-3242 Email: d.farielo@gmail.com LinkedIn: DouglasFFalcao

GitHub: Menphes

EXPERIENCES

Process Excellence and Digital Transformation Specialist

Merck Group

AUGUST 2021 - PRESENT
As a digital specialist and technical lead, I lead a group of 6 member on multiple projects for the Regulatory
Management & Trade Compliance team in LatAm, most of which consist in understanding, mapping (SDD & PDD) and automating current manual process done by the SMEs (Subject Matter Experts). Our automations focus on two main types of solution: Python-based development (Pandas, Selenium and SAP Scripting Tracker) and the Micrsoft Power Automate Platform. I'm also the business administrator of an internal Order Tracking Tool and the focal point between the Merck Business. focal point between the Merck Business, Merck IT and External IT Suppliers.

Data Analyst

Santander Brasil

MARCH 2019 - JULY 2021

Focus on financial data analysis, generation of management reports (Python/Pandas/Spark) in Hadoop environment, with emphasis on area KPIs (Spark/Impala), data ETL with Pentaho and RPAs (Python/Selenium). Administrator of an internal payment tool developed with C#.Net and Microsoft SQL Server. Lead of the structuring project for the migration of the entire Onboarding Payment pipéline to the Pipefy tool.

Web Content Developer

XManteiga

FEBRUARY 2017 - FEBRUARY 2019

Content development for geek entertainment and gaming news. Also focused on document revisions and Portuguese/English translations along with some Web Development (HTML5, CSS3, Python/Flask) for the platform.

PHP Developer

Somar Meteorologia Assessoria

APRIL 2016 - DECEMBER 2016 Development, documentation and quality testing of the Somar Meteorological Forecasting API (PHP/Laravel/Lumen) and the generation of weather graphic models (JavaScript/Highcharts), with Front-end support to the companies main website (HTML5/CSS3/JavaScript/PHP).

EDUCATION

Universidade do Grande ABC Santo André, SP

JANUARY 2007 - DECEMBER 2010 Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science.

COURSES

Advanced User Enterprise Architect

Grupo CTGI DECEMBER 2012 - DECEMBER 2012

FISK English Proficiency

FISK English School JANUARY 2001 - DECEMBER 2001

HONORS & AWARDS

Santander Hackathon: The Code Force - Innovation

Santander Brasil MARCH 2021

Digital Mindset Award for RM&TC

Merck Group DECEMBER 2022

LANGUAGES

English - Native Portuguese - Native **Spanish** - Intermediary

EXTRAS

Dual Citizenship (Brazilian/Portuguese) Availability to work anywhere in the LatAm Region and European Union.

Business Requirement Coordinator

Universidade Federal Fluminense

OCTOBER 2012 - APRIL 2016 Initially started as a Business Requirements Analyst focused on the mapping out of UML and Requirement Models using the Groups very own Information and Knowledge Management Model (GTecCom), after some well received project deliveries, promoted to Coordinator of a 4 member task force to delivery an extension of the project focused on the Process Flowcharts. Administrator of the Enterprise Architect tool, used to diagram all the projects Business Use Cases and information flowcharts.

Tech Lead

IBM

JULY 2011 - SEPTEMBER 2012

Initially started as a Web Developer for the GWPS Group inside of IBM, mainly focused on updating company flagship websites (Local and Global), creation of internal institutional portfolio sites and direct communication with international Team Managers and Tech Leads for internal Global projects. Promoted to Tech Lead of the internal tool ECM - Common Components.

PHP Developer

Lampada Global

NOVEMBER 2010 - JULY 2011 Senior Programmer's assistant and Customer Support for National and International clients, focused on minor changes and corrections to the SugarCRM Platform (PHP).

QUALIFICATIONS

Languages, Frameworks and Platforms:

Python; PHP, C#, R; Laravel/Lumen; HTML/CSS; XML/JSON; Javascript/JQuery; UML; Pascal/Delphi and Objective-C; ReactJS;

Operating Systems:

Microsoft Windows; Linux Ubuntu; MAC OS/iOS and Google Android:

Database:

MySQL; SQL Server; SQLite; PostgreSQL; Impala; Hive;

Tools, Libraries and Other Applications:

Pandas; NumPy; Flask; Django; Selenium; PyAutoGUI; Beautiful Soup, Pentaho; Microsoft Office; SugarCRM; Enterprise Architect; SAP; Android Studio;

Knowledge:

Data Analysis; RPAs; Rest API; Business Process Mapping; Customers Requirements Gathering; Team Coordination; Flowchart Diagramming; Use-Case Development (As Is/To Be); Git; SCRUM; Kanban;

INTERNATIONAL EXPERIENCES

United States - Golden, CO Study - Shelton Elementary Study - Bell Middle School JUNE 1994 - DECEMBER 1998